tradedirectory.com 2014-11-04

# Trade Directory - B2B, Manufacturers, Exporters, Importers, International Suppliers, UK Wholesalers, Traders and Trade Shows

_Effective from and Last Updated on:  26 May 2012_

This website is owned and operated by TradeDirectory.com Ltd. We are committed to protecting the privacy of our visitors while they interact with the content, products and services on this site (the “Site”). This Privacy Policy applies to the Site only. It does not apply to other websites to which we link. Because we gather certain types of information about our users, we want you to understand what information we collect about you, how we collect it, how that information is used, and how you can control our disclosure of it. You agree that your use of the Site signifies your assent to this Privacy Policy. If you do not agree with this Privacy Policy, please do not use the Site.

**1.  Information Collected**

We collect two types of information from you: i) information that you voluntarily provide to us (e.g. through a voluntary registration process, subscription to newsletter, business profile creation, advertising, publishing trade shows and partnering with us); and ii) Site statistics that are derived through automated tracking mechanisms.  

1.1 Voluntary Information

1.1.1 Registration

In order to fully access this Site, you must first complete the registration process, during which we will collect personal information about you. The information will include your name, country, email address and member type (e.g. buyer, seller or both). We do not collect personally identifiable information about you except when you specifically provide such information to us on a voluntary basis.  

By registering with us, you consent to the use and method of disclosure as described in this Privacy Policy.

1.1.2 Subscription

We also collect personal information about you when you subscribe to our newsletter. The information includes your name and email address. We do not collect personally identifiable information about you except when you specifically provide such information to us on a voluntary basis.  

1.1.3 Business Profile

We collect information about your business when you choose to use certain features of the Site, including but not limited to: i) buying leads ii) selling leads iii) products iv) advertising v) partnering with us vi) business networking vii) business consultancy viii) business directory ix) trade shows x) receiving emails, alerts, notifications and newsletters about leads, upcoming promotions and events and business news xi) participating in our forums, xii) commenting on articles and blog posts, and others. When you choose to use these additional features, we require you to fill in a form called “Business Profile”. We collect through this form your business details that may be required to complete a transaction, such as business name, business contact numbers, business address, business type (e.g. buyer, seller, manufacturer, exporter, importer, etc), business website, detailed business description, year business registered, and other details. 

1.1.4 Advertising

We also collect information about your business when you choose to advertise with us by placing a banner on the Site, such as website address.

1.1.5 Trade Shows

We collect information about your trade show when you choose to advertise your trade show on the Site, such as trade show title, date, venue, address, contact numbers, email, website, industry and other information related to trade show.

1.1.6 Partnership

We also collect information about your business when you choose to partner with us, such as business name, website address and business details.

Business information collected through Business Profile, Advertising, Trade Show and Partnership forms is publically available on the Site and accessible to all the internet users. By filling in the above sections (Business Profile, Advertising, Trade Show and Partnership) you give your full consent for the information provided by you in these sections to be published. You must not enter such personally identifiable information in these sections, which you do not want to be published publically on the Site.

1.2 Site Statistics

We utilise certain trusted third party software and other tracking technologies including Cookies (please refer to Section 2) to track Site usage, analyse data such as the number of unique visitors, sessions, pages viewed, browser, operating system, source address that a page request is coming from, your IP address and domain name, the date and time of the page request, the referring website (if any) and other parameters in the URL.

**2) Cookies**

Our site uses "cookies". Cookies enable us to serve secure pages to our users without asking them to sign in repeatedly. Most browsers allow you to control cookies, including whether or not to accept them and how to remove them. If a user's system is idle for a defined time, the cookie will expire, forcing the user to sign in again to continue their session. This prevents unauthorized access to the user's information while they are away from their computers.

You may set most browsers to notify you if you receive a cookie, or you may choose to block cookies with your browser, but please note that if you choose to erase or block your cookies, you will need to re-enter your original user ID and password to gain access to certain parts of the Site.

Third-Party Cookies: In the course of serving advertisements to this site, our third-party advertisers may place or recognize a unique "cookie" on your browser.

**3)  Referrals**

You may choose to invite friends to join TradeDirectory.com by sending invitation emails via our Tell a Friend feature. TradeDirectory.com stores the email addresses you provide so that the respondents may be added to your social network and also to send reminders of the invitations. TradeDirectory.com does not sell these email addresses or use them to send any other communication besides invitations and invitation reminders. Recipients of invitations may contact TradeDirectory.com to request removal of their information from our database.

**4) Recommendations**

You may choose to recommend a product advertised at TradeDirectory.com to your friends by emailing a page link via our ‘Email this page to a Friend’ feature. TradeDirectory.com stores the email addresses you provide so that the respondents may be added to your social network and also to send reminders of the recommendations. TradeDirectory.com does not sell these email addresses or use them to send any other communications besides recommendations and recommendation reminders. Recipients of recommendations may contact TradeDirectory.com to request removal of their information from our database.

**5)  Credit Card Information**

_We do not store your credit card details._

**6)  How We Use Your Information**

6.1 Personal Information

TradeDirectory.com only uses your personal information for the original purposes it was given. Your personal information will not be sold or otherwise transferred to unaffiliated third parties without your approval at the time of collection.

TradeDirectory.com will not disclose, use or give any personal information to third parties for any purposes other than to our suppliers and other third parties who need to know in order to deliver services on behalf of TradeDirectory.com unless required to do so by law. Further, TradeDirectory.com reserves the right to contact you regarding matters relevant to the underlying service provided and/or the information collected.

TRADEDIRECTORY.COM WILL NOT DISCLOSE PERSONALLY IDENTIFIABLE INFORMATION TO ADVERTISERS, BUYERS, SELLERS OR EVENT ORGANISERS UNLESS AND UNTIL YOU CHOOSE TO CONTACT THEM YOURSELF USING THE CONTACT MEMBER OR CONTACT ORGANISER, ETC FORMS ON TRADEDIRECTORY.COM. IF YOU DO NOT WISH YOUR PERSONALLY INDENTIFIABLE INFORMATION TO BE DISCLOSED TO WHOM YOU CONTACT, PLEASE DO NOT USE CONTACT MEMBER OR CONTACT ORGANISER, ETC FORMS.

Please note that personally identifiable information is used only to provide you with a more enjoyable, convenient online experience and to help us identify and/or provide information, products or services that may be of interest to you. We use your personally identifiable information to support and enhance your use of the Site and its features, including without limitation: fulfilling your order; providing customer service; tracking email invitations you send; and otherwise supporting your use of the Site.

We may use your business address, email address, phone, mobile or fax numbers to contact you regarding notifications, alerts, notices, surveys, new services or offers and other communications relevant to the use of the Site. We may use your personal as well as business information to execute marketing campaigns, promotions or advertising messages on behalf of third parties; however, they will not be disclosed to such third parties unless and until you respond to the marketing, promotional or advertising messages.

TradeDirectory.com may use your personal information for target advertising toward you based on things such as region, gender, interests, goals, habits, etc.

Also, we may share personally identifiable or other information with our parent, subsidiaries, divisions, and affiliates.

We may transfer personally identifiable information as an asset in connection with a proposed or actual merger or sale (including any transfers made as part of an insolvency or bankruptcy proceeding) involving all or part of our business or as part of a corporate reorganization, stock sale or other change in control.

TradeDirectory.com may disclose Contact Information in special cases where we have reason to believe that disclosing this information is necessary to identify, contact or bring legal action against someone who may be violating our terms and conditions of use or may be causing injury or interference with our rights, property, our customers or anyone who could be harmed by such activities.

WE ARE NOT LIABLE OR RESPONSIBLE FOR THE PERSONALLY IDENTIFIABLE OR OTHER INFORMATION YOU CHOOSE TO SUBMIT IN FORUMS, BLOGS, CHAT ROOMS OR ANY OTHER PUBLICLY ACCESSIBLE AREA OF THE SITE.

You will receive notice when your personally identifiable information might be provided to any third party for any reason other than as set forth in this Privacy Policy, and you will have an opportunity to request that we do not share such information.

We use non-identifying and aggregate information to better design our website and for business and administrative purposes. We may also use or share with third parties for any purpose aggregated data that contains no personally identifiable information.

6.2. Business Information

TradeDirectory.com is a business to business portal. The sole purpose of our Site is to disseminate information about manufacturers, exporters, importers, distributors, wholesalers, sellers, buyers and trade show organisers to the interested parties. TradeDirectory.com provides space and slots to the registered users to publish information about their businesses, events and shows and also upload images and catalogues of their products. Any information collected through these features will be immediately available for and accessible by both guest and registered users of the Site.

6.3. Site Usage Information  

Site statistics are collected in order to better understand our Web site usage, and enhance the performance of services to maintain and operate the Site and certain features on the Site. We may use third parties to host the Site; operate various features available on the Site; send emails; analyse data; provide search results and links and assist in fulfilling your orders.  

**7) How We Protect Your Information**

We are committed to protecting the information we receive from you. We take appropriate security measures to protect your information against unauthorised access to or unauthorised alteration, disclosure or destruction of data. To prevent unauthorised access, maintain data accuracy, and ensure the correct use of information, we maintain appropriate physical, electronic, and managerial procedures to safeguard and secure the information and data stored on our system. While no computer system is completely secure, we believe the measures we have implemented reduce the likelihood of security problems to a level appropriate to the type of data involved.

**8) How You Can Protect Your Information**

Please ensure you keep your password secret and do not disclose it to anyone or record it in any way that may be discovered by anyone. No personal will ever ask you for your password via phone, fax, mail or email.  Always sign out of your account and close your browser once you have finished your work.

**9) Third Party Advertising**

Advertisements appearing on this Site may be delivered to you by TradeDirectory.com or our web advertising partners. Our web advertising partners may set cookies. Doing this allows the advertising partners to recognize your computer each time they send you an advertisement. In this way, they may compile information about where you, or others who are using your computer, saw their advertisements and determine which advertisements are clicked. This information allows an advertising partner to deliver targeted advertisements that they believe will be of most interest to you. TradeDirectory.com does not have access to or control of the cookies that may be placed by the third party advertising servers of ad partners.  

This privacy statement covers the use of cookies by TradeDirectory.com and does not cover the use of cookies by any of its advertisers.  

**10)  Accessing and Updating Your Personal and Business Information and Preferences**

We provide mechanisms for updating and correcting your personal and business information for many of our services.  You may modify or remove any of your personal or business information at any time by logging into your account and accessing features such as Account Settings and Business Profile, etc.  

**11)  Email Choice/Opt-out**

If you no longer wish to receive updates, notifications or newsletters you may opt-out of receiving these communications by changing your “My Alerts” settings in your “My Account” area.  

**12) Children's Privacy and Parental Controls**

We do not solicit any personal information from children. If you are not 18 or older, you are not authorised to use the Site. Parents should be aware that there are parental control tools available online that can be used to prevent children from submitting information online without parental permission or from accessing material that is harmful to minors.

**13) Disclaimer to Security**

By consenting to the Terms of Use of the Site and the Privacy Policy, you consent that no data transmission over the Internet is completely secure. We cannot guarantee or warrant the security of any information you provide to us; you transmit such information to us at your own risk.

**14) Notification of Changes**

TradeDirectory.com reserves the right to change this Privacy Policy from time to time at its sole discretion. If at some point in the future, there is a change to our Privacy Policy, unless we obtain your express consent, such change will only apply to information collected after the revised Privacy Policy took effect. Your continued use of the Site indicates your assent to the Privacy Policy as posted.  

**15)  Contact Information**

 If you have any questions or concerns regarding this Privacy Policy please contact:

TradeDirectory.com Ltd

33 Yorkshire Street  
Oldham  
OL1 3RZ  
United Kingdom

Company Reg No: 07345656

Tel: +44 (0)161 620 6840  
Fax: +44 (0)161 284 3159

Email: mail@ tradedirectory.com
